A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Civil War Commission, 1952-1966 (bulk 1958-1965)
Library of Virginia
- Series IV.The Wartime Papers of Robert E. Lee, 1959-1961 (photostats and card index: 1832-1870)., Extent: 21 cu. ft. (Box 85-149.)
  - Transcripts, 1833-1865.
    - Chapter Sixteen.
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 June 24. (Box 103, Folder 53)
      - To General Wade Hampton, 1864 June 25. (Box 103, Folder 54)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 June 25. (Box 103, Folder 55)
      - Taylor to General F. Lee, 1864 June 26. (Box 103, Folder 56)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 June 26. (Box 103, Folder 57)
      - To J. Davis, 1864 June 26. (Box 103, Folder 58)
      - To Wife, 1864 June 26. (Box 103, Folder 59)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 June 28. (Box 103, Folder 60)
      - To Miss Mildred C. Lee, 1864 June 28. (Box 103, Folder 61)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 June 29. (Box 103, Folder 62)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 June 29. (Box 103, Folder 63)
      - To Wife, 1864 June 30. (Box 103, Folder 64)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 July 1. (Box 103, Folder 65)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 July 2. (Box 103, Folder 66)
      - To Miss M.C. Lee, 1864 July 5. (Box 103, Folder 67)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 July 5. (Box 103, Folder 68)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 July 6. (Box 103, Folder 69)
      - To Wife, 1864 July 7. (Box 103, Folder 70)
      - To General R.S. Ewell, 1864 July 9. (Box 103, Folder 71)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 July 10. (Box 103, Folder 72)
      - To Wife, 1864 July 10. (Box 103, Folder 73)
      - To General J. Early, 1864 July 11. (Box 103, Folder 74)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 July 12. (Box 103, Folder 75)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 July 12. (Box 103, Folder 76)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 July 19. (Box 103, Folder 77)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 July 23. (Box 103, Folder 78)
      - To R.S. Ewell, 1864 July 24. (Box 103, Folder 79)
      - To G.W.C. Lee, 1864 July 24. (Box 103, Folder 80)
      - To R.H. Anderson, 1864 July 27. (Box 103, Folder 81)
      - To General R.S. Ewell, 1864 July 28. (Box 103, Folder 82)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 July 30. (Box 103, Folder 83)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 July 30. (Box 103, Folder 84)
      - To Wife, 1864 July 31. (Box 103, Folder 85)
      - To Wife, 1864 August 7. (Box 103, Folder 86)
      - To General G.E. Pickett, 1864 August 9. (Box 103, Folder 87)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 August 9. (Box 103, Folder 88)
      - To General R.S. Ewell, 1864 August 10. (Box 104, Folder 1)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 August 11. (Box 104, Folder 2)
      - To General R.H. Anderson, 1864 August 11. (Box 104, Folder 3)
      - To General Wade Hampton, 1864 August 11. (Box 104, Folder 4)
      - To General R.S. Ewell, 1864 August 12. (Box 104, Folder 5)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 August 12. (Box 104, Folder 6)
      - To General R.H. Anderson, 1864 August 12. (Box 104, Folder 7)
      - To General Wade Hampton, 1864 August 14. (Box 104, Folder 8)
      - To General C.W. Field, 1864 August 14. (Box 104, Folder 9)
      - To General R.S. Ewell, 1864 August 14. (Box 104, Folder 10)
      - To General C.W. Field, 1864 August 14. (Box 104, Folder 11)
      - To Wife, 1864 August 14. (Box 104, Folder 12)
      - Taylor to Major General C.W. Field, 1864 August 15. (Box 104, Folder 13)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 August 16. (Box 104, Folder 14)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 August 16. (Box 104, Folder 15)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 August 16. (Box 104, Folder 16)
      - Taylor To Major General C.M. Wilcox, 1864 August 18. (Box 104, Folder 17)
      - To Secretary of War, 1864 August 18. (Box 104, Folder 18)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 August 20. (Box 104, Folder 19)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 August 20. (Box 104, Folder 20)
      - To Major General Wade Hampton, 1864 August 21. (Box 104, Folder 21)
      - Taylor to Charles G. Talcott, 1864 August 21. (Box 104, Folder 22)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 August 21. (Box 104, Folder 23)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 August 22. (Box 104, Folder 24)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 August 23. (Box 104, Folder 25)
      - To General Wade Hampton, 1864 August 24. (Box 104, Folder 26)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 August 26. (Box 104, Folder 27)
      - To General J. Early, 1864 August 26. (Box 104, Folder 28)
      - To Wife, 1864 August 28. (Box 104, Folder 29)
      - To J. Davis, 1864 September 2. (Box 104, Folder 30)
      - To Wife, 1864 September 5. (Box 104, Folder 31)
      - To General Braxton Bragg, 1864 September 10. (Box 104, Folder 32)
      - To General Braxton Bragg, 1864 September 12. (Box 104, Folder 33)
      - To R.H. Anderson, 1864 September 17. (Box 104, Folder 34)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 September 17. (Box 104, Folder 35)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 September 17. (Box 104, Folder 36)
      - To Wife, 1864 September 18. (Box 104, Folder 37)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 September 20. (Box 104, Folder 38)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 September 23. (Box 104, Folder 39)
      - To General R.H. Anderson, 1864 September 23. (Box 104, Folder 40)
      - To General J.A. Early, 1864 September 23. (Box 104, Folder 41)
      - To Governor William Smith, 1864 September 24. (Box 104, Folder 42)
      - To General John Echols, 1864 September 24. (Box 104, Folder 43)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 September 26. (Box 104, Folder 44)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 September 29. (Box 104, Folder 45)
      - To General Braxton Bragg, 1864 September 29. (Box 104, Folder 46)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 September 29. (Box 104, Folder 47)
      - To General R.S. Ewell, 1864 September 29. (Box 104, Folder 48)
      - to General R.S. Ewell, 1864 September 29. (Box 104, Folder 49)
      - To General S. Cooper, 1864 September 29. (Box 104, Folder 50)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 September 30. (Box 104, Folder 51)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 1. (Box 104, Folder 52)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 4. (Box 104, Folder 53)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 7. (Box 104, Folder 54)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 7. (Box 104, Folder 55)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 9. (Box 104, Folder 56)
      - To General A.P. Hill, 1864 October 10. (Box 104, Folder 57)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 13. (Box 104, Folder 58)
      - To General J. Breckinridge, 1864 October 20. (Box 104, Folder 59)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 20. (Box 104, Folder 60)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 21. (Box 104, Folder 61)
      - To Wife, 1864 October 25. (Box 104, Folder 62)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 October 27. (Box 104, Folder 63)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 October 27. (Box 104, Folder 64)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 October 27. (Box 104, Folder 65)
      - To J. Seddon, 1864 October 28. (Box 104, Folder 66)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 November 2. (Box 104, Folder 67)
      - To Wife, 1864 November 15. (Box 104, Folder 68)
      - To Wife, 1864 November 16. (Box 104, Folder 69)
      - To Agnes, 1864 November 20. (Box 104, Folder 70)
      - To General Wade Hampton, 1864 November 21. (Box 104, Folder 71)
      - To Wife, 1864 November 25. (Box 104, Folder 72)
      - To Wife, 1864 November 30. (Box 104, Folder 73)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 December 5. (Box 104, Folder 74)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 December 7. (Box 104, Folder 75)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 December 8. (Box 104, Folder 76)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 December 10. (Box 104, Folder 77)
      - To J.A. Seddon, 1864 December 10. (Box 104, Folder 78)
      - To G.W.C. Lee, 1864 December 13. (Box 104, Folder 79)
      - To General S. Cooper, 1864 December 13. (Box 104, Folder 80)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 December 14. (Box 104, Folder 81)
      - To Wife, 1864 December 17. (Box 104, Folder 82)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1864 December 19. (Box 104, Folder 83)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1864 December 26. (Box 104, Folder 84)
      - To Wife, 1864 December 30. (Box 104, Folder 85)
      - To General J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 January 10. (Box 104, Folder 86)
      - To Honorable J.A. Seddon, 1865 January 11. (Box 104, Folder 87)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 January 15. (Box 104, Folder 88)
      - To Secretary of War, 1865 January 16. (Box 104, Folder 89)
      - To General W. Terry, 1865 January 16. (Box 104, Folder 90)
      - To Wife, 1865 January 17. (Box 104, Folder 91)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 January 19. (Box 104, Folder 92)
      - To William P. Miles, 1865 January 19. (Box 104, Folder 93)
      - To Honorable James A. Seddon, 1865 January 27. (Box 105, Folder 1)
      - To Wife, 1865 January 29. (Box 105, Folder 2)
      - To Wife, 1865 February 3. (Box 105, Folder 3)
      - To General S. Cooper, 1865 February 4. (Box 105, Folder 4)
      - To General S. Cooper, 1865 February 6. (Box 105, Folder 5)
      - General Orders, Number 1, 1865 February 9. (Box 105, Folder 6)
      - To Honorable J.A. Seddon, 1865 February 8. (Box 105, Folder 7)
      - To William P. Miles, 1865 February 9. (Box 105, Folder 8)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 February 9. (Box 105, Folder 9)
      - To Wife, 1865 February 11. (Box 105, Folder 10)
      - To Wife, 1865 February 12. (Box 105, Folder 11)
      - To A.H. Stevens and Others, 1865 February 13. (Box 105, Folder 12)
      - Circular, 1865 February 18. (Box 105, Folder 13)
      - To Wife, 1865 February 18. (Box 105, Folder 14)
      - To J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 February 19. (Box 105, Folder 15)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 February 19. (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Chapter Seventeen.
      - To J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 February 21. (Box 105, Folder 17)
      - To Wife, 1865 February 21. (Box 105, Folder 18)
      - To Lt. General James Longstreet, 1865 February 22. (Box 105, Folder 19)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 February 23. (Box 105, Folder 20)
      - To Honorable J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 February 24. (Box 105, Folder 21)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 March 2. (Box 105, Folder 22)
      - To Lt. General U.S. Grant, 1865 March 2. (Box 105, Folder 23)
      - To Honorable J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 3. (Box 105, Folder 24)
      - To Honorable J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 9. (Box 105, Folder 25)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 March 10. (Box 105, Folder 26)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 March 14. (Box 105, Folder 27)
      - To Honorable J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 21. (Box 105, Folder 28)
      - To J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 25. (Box 105, Folder 29)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 March 26. (Box 105, Folder 30)
      - General Orders, Number 8, 1865 March 27. (Box 105, Folder 31)
      - To Wife, 1865 March 28. (Box 105, Folder 32)
      - To Agnes, 1865 March 28. (Box 105, Folder 33)
      - To Agnes, 1865 March 29. (Box 105, Folder 34)
      - To Honorable J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 29. (Box 105, Folder 35)
      - To Honorable J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 29. (Box 105, Folder 36)
      - To J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 30. (Box 105, Folder 37)
      - To Agnes, 1865 March 31. (Box 105, Folder 38)
      - To Honorable J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 March 31. (Box 105, Folder 39)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 April 1. (Box 105, Folder 40)
      - To Secretary of War, 1865 April 1. (Box 105, Folder 41)
      - To Agnes, 1865 April 1. (Box 105, Folder 42)
      - To Honorable J. Breckinridge, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 43)
      - To J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 44)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 45)
      - To J.C. Breckinridge, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 46)
      - To General H. Heth, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 47)
      - To Lt. General R.S. Ewell, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 48)
      - To Lt. General R.S. Ewell, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 49)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 50)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 April 2. (Box 105, Folder 51)
      - To General R.S. Ewell, 1865 April 3. (Box 105, Folder 52)
      - To Lt. General R.S. Ewell, 1865 April 4. (Box 105, Folder 53)
      - To Lt. General R.H. Anderson, 1865 April 5. (Box 105, Folder 54)
      - To General J.B. Gordon, 1865 April 6. (Box 105, Folder 55)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 April 6. (Box 105, Folder 56)
      - To General U.S. Grant, 1865 April 7. (Box 105, Folder 57)
      - To General U.S. Grant, 1865 April 8. (Box 105, Folder 58)
      - To General U.S. Grant, 1865 April 9. (Box 105, Folder 59)
      - To Lt. General U.S. Grant, 1865 April 9. (Box 105, Folder 60)
      - To Lt. General U.S. Grant, 1865 April 9. (Box 105, Folder 61)
      - To General U.S. Grant, 1865 April 9. (Box 105, Folder 62)
      - Special Orders, Number (?), 1865 April 9. (Box 105, Folder 63)
      - General Order, Number 9, 1865 April 10. (Box 105, Folder 64)
      - Lee's Parole, 1865 April 9. (Box 105, Folder 65)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 April 12. (Box 105, Folder 66)
      - To Jefferson Davis, 1865 April 20. (Box 105, Folder 67)
      - Narratives, undated. (Box 105, Folder 68)
  - Unused Letters and Papers, 1833-1870.
    - 1833. (Box 106)
    - 1853. (Box 106)
    - 1855. (Box 106)
    - 1861 January. (Box 106)
    - 1861 February. (Box 106)
    - 1861 March. (Box 106)
    - 1861 April. (Box 106)
    - 1861 May 1-3. (Box 106)
    - 1861 May 4-8. (Box 107)
    - 1861 May 8-15. (Box 108)
    - 1861 May 15-24. (Box 109)
    - 1861 May 25-29. (Box 110)
    - 1861 May 30-31. (Box 111)
    - 1861 June 1-10. (Box 111)
    - 1861 June 11-20. (Box 112)
    - 1861 June 21-30. (Box 113)
    - 1861 July 1-12. (Box 114)
    - 1861 July 13-31. (Box 115)
    - 1861 August 1-16. (Box 115)
    - 1861 August 17-31. (Box 116)
    - 1861 September. (Box 116)
    - 1861 October. (Box 116)
    - 1861 November 4-20. (Box 116)
    - 1861 November 21-29. (Box 117)
    - 1861 December 3-22. (Box 117)
    - 1861 December 23-31. (Box 118)
    - 1862 January 1-11. (Box 118)
    - 1862 January 13-31. (Box 119)
    - 1862 February 1-13. (Box 119)
    - 1862 February 14-28. (Box 120)
    - 1862 March 1-14. (Box 120)
    - 1862 March 15-31. (Box 121)
    - 1862 April 1-2. (Box 121)
    - 1862 April 3-18. (Box 122)
    - 1862 April 19-28. (Box 123)
    - 1862 April 29-30. (Box 124)
    - 1862 May 1-8. (Box 124)
    - 1862 May 9-20. (Box 125)
    - 1862 May 21-31. (Box 126)
    - 1862 June 1-11. (Box 126)
    - 1862 June 12-26. (Box 127)
    - 1862 July 3-21. (Box 127)
    - 1862 July 23-31. (Box 128)
    - 1862 August 1-7. (Box 128)
    - 1862 August 8-31. (Box 129)
    - 1862 September 2-21. (Box 129)
    - 1862 September 22-30. (Box 130)
    - 1862 October 1-19. (Box 130)
    - 1862 October 20-31. (Box 131)
    - 1862 November 3-18. (Box 131)
    - 1862 November 19-30. (Box 132)
    - 1862 December. (Box 132)
    - 1863 January. (Box 133)
    - 1863 February. (Box 133)
    - 1863 March 2-19. (Box 133)
    - 1863 March 20-31. (Box 134)
    - 1863 April. (Box 134)
    - 1863 May 4-22. (Box 134)
    - 1863 May 23-31. (Box 135)
    - 1863 June. (Box 135)
    - 1863 July. (Box 135)
    - 1863 August. (Box 136)
    - 1863 September. (Box 136)
    - 1863 October. (Box 136)
    - 1863 November. (Box 137)
    - 1863 December. (Box 137)
    - 1864 January 1-22. (Box 137)
    - 1864 January 24-31. (Box 138)
    - 1864 February. (Box 138)
    - 1864 March. (Box 138)
    - 1864 April 1-19. (Box 138)
    - 1864 April 20-30. (Box 139)
    - 1864 May. (Box 139)
    - 1864 June. (Box 140)
    - 1864 July 1-13. (Box 140)
    - 1864 July 15-31. (Box 141)
    - 1864 August. (Box 141)
    - 1864 September 2-19. (Box 141)
    - 1864 September 20-29. (Box 142)
    - 1864 October. (Box 142)
    - 1864 November 1-20. (Box 142)
    - 1864 November 21-30. (Box 143)
    - 1864 December. (Box 143)
    - 1865 January. (Box 143)
    - 1865 February 2-9. (Box 143)
    - 1865 February 11-28. (Box 144)
    - 1865 March. (Box 144)
    - 1865 April. (Box 144)
    - 1866-1870. (Box 144)
    - Miscellaneous documents, undated. (Box 144)
    - Letters (Confederate Archives), 1863. (Box 145-146)
    - Letters (Confederate Archives), 1864. (Box 146-147)
    - Special Orders (Confederate Archives), 1863. (Box 147-148)
    - Letters and Telegrams, Chapter 2, Volume 83 (Confederate Archives), 1863-1864. (Box 148)
    - The War of the Rebellion, Series I. Volume 40, Parts 1-3, 1864. (Box 148)
    - The War of the Rebellion, Series I. Volume 42, Parts 1-3, 1864. (Box 148)
    - The War of the Rebellion, Series I. Volume 43, Part 1 through Volume 46, Part 3, 1864-1865. (Box 149)
    - The War of the Rebellion, Series I. Volume 51, Part 2, 1862-1865. (Box 149)
    - The War of the Rebellion, Series II., III., and IV., 1862-1865. (Box 149)
- Series V. Miscellaneous Records (Accession 53645), 1936-2011., Extent: .9 cu. ft. (Box 1-2)
  Miscellaneous records, 1936-2011, are arranged by record type and contain the miscellaneous files of Richmond historian Robert W. Waitt, Jr., who also served as the Executive Secretary Richmond Civil War Centennial Committee, as well as later records collected by Roberty Kingery. These research materials include articles, brochures, clippings, and publications.
  Arranged alphabetically by record type and alphabetically within each type.
  - Articles: Miscellaneous, 1965-1990. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brochure: Abraham Lincoln - The Great Emancipation, 1956. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochure: Arizona State Parks, undated. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brochure: The Civil War Horse, undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brochure: Directory of Officials (1861-1865), undated. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brochure: Illustrated Gettysburg Battlefield map, 1936. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brochure: The Nation's Most Historic Airport - Richard E. Byrd Flying Field, undated. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brochure: Oklahoma Civil War Centennial, 1963. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brochure: Picacho Pass - Arizona's Civil War Story, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brochure: USS Cairo - The Story of a Civil War Gunboat, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - News clippings, 2011, undated. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brochure: Proceedings: Redidcation Program honoring the memory of the gallant New Jersey men who in the battles of Salem Church, the Wilderness, and Spotsylvania Court House, 1964 May 16. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Publication: Abraham Lincoln - Bibliography, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Publication: Abraham Lincoln - Calendar, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Publication: Abraham Lincoln - The Critter in Marble, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Publication: Abraham Lincoln - During Two Journeys, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Publication: Abraham Lincoln - Lincoln's Other Scrapbook, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Publication: Facts About the Civil War, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Publication: Guide for the Observance of the Centennial of the Civil War, 1959. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Publication: Iowa in the Civil War, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Publication: The Lincoln Ideals, undated. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Publication: Lincoln Memorial, 1956. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Publication: Lincoln Sesquicentennial (1809-1959), 1958. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Publication: Massachusetts in the Civil War, 1960. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Publication: Ohio Handbook of the Civil War, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Publication: Our Women of the Sixties, 1963. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publication: The Symbol and the Sword, 1962. (Box 2, Folder 7)